# MARÍA DE LOS ÁNGELES LASA

#### **Political Data Scientist**

@ ma.angeleslasa@gmail.com **❤** @Condolasa

in marialasa

marialasa.ar marialasa



### **ABOUT ME**

Political Data Scientist with 10+ years of experience in mixed methods research. Currently helping governments, CSOs, and NGOs to conduct research, measure, evaluate, and report the impact of their initiatives.

I have led technical projects related to media literacy, mis- and disinformation, judicial protection of Venezuelan migrants, migrant integration, affective polarization, participation of women in politics, "anti-vax" movements, COVID-19, and sports for development (S4D).

Excellent communication skills to present technical analysis to nontechnical audiences.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Data Analytics Lead

Gender Justice Data Hub, Global Fund for Women

Jul 2023 - Ongoing

San Francisco, US (Remote)

#### Gender Justice Data Hub Fellow

**Global Fund for Women** 

Dec 2022 - Jun 2023

San Francisco, US (Remote)

#### Director of Legacy and Sustainability

XIX Pan American and Parapan American Games Santiago 2023

May 2022 - Dec 2022

Santiago, CL

## Research and Data Analytics Manager

Movilizatorio

**Apr** 2020 – Apr 2022

Bogotá, CO (Remote)

### Open Data Policy Advisor

**Unit of Open Government, OECD** 

**i** Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

Paris, FR

#### **Project Consultant**

Oxford Development Consultancy

Ct 2018 - Mar 2019

Oxford, UK

## Head of Legacy and Sustainability

**Buenos Aires 2018 Youth Olympic Games** 

**Apr** 2017 - Sep 2018

Buenos Aires, AR

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Public Policy **University of Oxford (GB)** 

**Sep 2018 - Nov 2019** 

Ph.D. in Political Science Università degli Studi di Camerino (IT)

**i** Jun 2011 - Dec 2014

B.A. in International Relations Universidad Católica de Córdoba (AR)

Feb 2004 - Feb 2009

#### STRENGTHS

Writing Skills Storytelling Creativity **Public Speaking Analytical Skills** 

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

R Python HTML SPSS MS Excel Gephi

### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish **English** Italian



## **HONORS & AWARDS**



**TEDxSpeaker** 

TEDxUCC & TEDxRecoleta, 2016







#### **RESEARCH & TEACHING**

## Associate Professor of Politics of Policymaking

#### **Universidad Comunera**

**a** Aug 2020 - Aug 2022

Asunción, PY (Remote)

# Guest Lecturer of State Theory and Public Policy Universidad Torcuato Di Tella

**Aug** 2021 - Jan 2022

Buenos Aires, AR

### Visiting Researcher @ Department of Pol.Sci.

#### **Universidad de Los Andes**

**Sep 2013 - Nov 2013** 

Bogotá, CO

#### Visiting Researcher @ LLILAS

#### **University of Texas at Austin**

**Feb** 2013 - Aug 2013

Austin, US

# Graduate Teaching Assistant in Introduction to IR Universidad Nacional de Villa María

Feb 2009 - Dec 2009

Villa María, AR

### **GRANTS & SCHOLARSHIPS**

Erasmus+ Grant

UOxford-OECD Summer Placement (FR), 2019. €800.

iTrek Scholarship

Oxford-Blavatnik Policy Programme (IL), 2019.

Blavatnik Scholarship

University of Oxford (GB), 2018 - 2019. £7,376.

Chevening Award

British Government (GB), 2018 - 2019. £47,569.

Fulbright Scholarship

UMass Young Leaders Program (US), 2014. U\$8,000.

CUIA Scholarship

Italian Government (IT), 2011 - 2014. €72,200.

Fundación Carolina Scholarship

Complutense Summer School (ES), 2011. €4,000.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

 ARGARAÑÁZ, M.; LASA, M. et al. (2018). Protocolo para la gestión de eventos sostenibles. United Nations Argentina & UNDP.

 BER, M.; DHRU, K. LASA, M. (2011). "Rethinking leadership, re-founding leadership". In St. Gallen Wings of Excellence Award, 41 St. Gallen Symposium. St. Gallen: Universität St. Gallen, p. 24-31.

#### **OTHER STUDIES**

# PgDipl. in Big Data FLACSO (AR)

Apr 2023 - Ongoing

#### Data Science Summer School Hertie School Data Science Lab (DE)

**J**ul 2022 - Aug 2022

# PgCert. in Data Science Universidad Torcuato Di Tella (AR)

Apr 2020 - Oct 2020

# PgDipl. in Policy Evaluation Universitat Pompeu Fabra (ES)

**Mar 2017 - Dec 2017** 

#### **AFFILIATIONS**

National

Chevening Alumni<sup>1</sup>, CARI<sup>2</sup>, CADAL<sup>3</sup>

- <sup>1</sup> Board of Directors, 2020 2024
- <sup>2</sup> Executive Board YG, 2018 & 2021
- <sup>3</sup> Academic Council, 2022-2023

## International

Oxford Union, R-Ladies Global, Red de Politólogas & YLAI

## **VOLUNTEER WORK**

OxCGRT, University of Oxford Data Analyst, 2020 – 2021

South American Business Forum Contest Jury, 2012 - Ongoing

Model United Nations (MUN)
Academic Advisor, 2005 - Ongoing

### **CAUSES**

Gender Equality Civic Tech

Democracy and participation Education

### PERSONAL INTERESTS

Cold War DPRK Bass Violin
Podcasts Blogs Photography Tetris
Lego Travels Space Exploration